#### **Ben Anderson**

design.benanderson@gmail.com · (720) 297-6474 Portfolio Site LinkedIn Profile

Hello! My name is Ben Anderson <u>\*\*</u> and I've been designing SaaS web apps for seven years. Since 2021 I've been focused on design systems:

**UI components and patterns** that are highly usable, consistent, scalable, responsive and accessible.

Figma libraries that empower designers to deliver their best work, fast.

**Documentation and training** resources that equip anyone in the org to make smart, systems-oriented design choices.

**Design-to-Dev processes** that ensure a precise and strategic transition from vision to code.

Experience

## GridX ←

Lead Product Designer, UX/UI (December 2022 – Present)

## JumpCloud 🥧

Senior Product Designer, Platform Experience (August 2021 – November 2022)

**Stratus Web Design System** serves all of JumpCloud's web consoles and 18+ UX designers. I created an ecosystem of web UI components and patterns to scale across our platform, Figma libraries with 80+ UI components, documentation and training resources, and handoff processes to translate designs into Vue-based code.

**JumpCloud MTP** allows IT administrators to serve multiple client organizations from a single pane of glass. I've led UX for this product since 2021, focusing on new features like integrations, license usage and payment history. I also developed new UI components and patterns for navigation, list and detail views, status cards, bulk actions, and quick actions for application across all other JumpCloud platforms.

**Password Manager** lets JumpCloud end users securely store and share passwords. I supported this project by designing key flows for onboarding, user enrollment, shared folder management, and usage insights. It also provided a great opportunity to apply design system patterns and new UI components.

**Asset Directory** helps IT admins to provision, track and manage all of the hardware and software assets used by employees across their org. I supported this project by designing list and detail views, asset creation flows, user assignment flows, and usage insights.



Senior Product Designer (July 2019 – April 2021) Product Designer (March 2018 – June 2019)

**GlobalMeet Webcast** is a live video streaming platform for enterprise companies. I led a vision-oriented redesign for this web app by creating all new UI, navigation and page structures, as well as flows for event creation, event delivery, recording, chat and analytics. I also turned all that into a high-fidelity prototype for user testing and a promotional video.

**GlobalMeet Mobile** is a platform for web conferencing and unified business communications. I led UX for these iOS and Android apps from 2018 to 2020, focusing on UI updates and new features like smart notifications, messaging, calling and video conferencing.

# ReadyTalk $\bigcirc$

User Experience Designer (January 2017 – February 2018) Visual Designer (December 2015 – December 2016)

**Illuminate Webcast** is a live and simulated-live video streaming platform purpose-built for marketers. I led UX for this new web app by creating branding, UI, navigation and page structures as well as flows for event creation, event delivery, recording, chat and white label customization.

**ReadyTalk.com** provides marketing and support information for ReadyTalk's conferencing and webcast products. I redesigned the site to make it easier for potential customers to find the right solutions, understanding pricing, dive into technical specs and self-serve or connect with sales. It was also a great opportunity to update the visual identity while building on existing brand recognition.

**Foxden Video Conferencing** allows users to virtually meet and share content without downloads or plugins. I designed the visual identity, website, marketing collateral, and promotional videos.



Industrial Designer (July 2013 – November 2015)

**Nuby** makes toys, teethers and feeding products for babies and toddlers. I designed new products from sketch to refined drawings, to 3D models, renders and prototypes, to materials and finishes, and finally to manufactured pieces for worldwide distribution.

## Education

# University of Bradford 🎓

MBA - Innovation, Enterprise and Circular Economy (2015 – 2018)

# Savannah College of Art and Design 🎨

BFA - Industrial Design (2007 – 2011)

Tools

### Web

HTML + CSS (I like to mock with markup whenever possible)

## UX

Figma (preferred), Sketch, XD, ProtoPie, Usertesting.com

### Adobe

Photoshop, Illustrator, AfterEffects

View my work at <u>andersonxd.com</u>